Profile

After bringing up three daughters who are now teenagers, I'm relaunching my career as UX designer, front-end developer and information architect.

I'm a former software developer and had various jobs as software developer in Office Communication Systems and Geographic Information Systems in Germany and England before starting a family.

An experienced multi tasker and dedicated team player, I'm highly motivated, goal-driven and conscientious with superb organizational and management skills.

I'm completely fluent in German and English and speak French well.

Translation, Transcription, Tutoring

LogueWorks

▶ [2015 – 2016] Worked as freelancer doing medical transcription and translation for LogueWorks

Tutoring

▶ [2015-2016] Online Tutoring in German using WizIQ, Scribblar and Skype

Volunteering Experience in Media, Documentary Film Making and Research

The Steve Mayo Show, WVOX 1460AM

▶ [2013 – 2016] — Co-host of the Steve Mayo Show (New Rochelle, Metropolitan New York)

Crowdfunding for Documentary Film about the Financial Crisis

▶ [2014-2015] Organized Indiegogo Crowdfunding campaign to raise money for documentary Subprime 2.0

Work Experience in Software Development and Project Management (1992-1997)

Smallworld Systems Ltd (Cambridge, UK)

▶ [1995 – 1997] Consultant for Geographic Information Systems Software development; Account and Project Management; Business Development

Lloyds Bank (London, UK)

▶ [1994] Software Developer

Member of the Lotus Notes development team in the Information Systems department

Software AG (Darmstadt, Germany)

▶ [1992-1994] Software Developer

Member of the development team for Entire Office Workstation, Software AG's CON-NECT office communication system

Born und Partner (Darmstadt, Germany)

▶ [1992] Software Developer

Implemented programs in C and CBase for an information management system designed for a German manufacturing firm

Work Experience in Teaching (1985-1989)

Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy (Medford, MA)

▶ [1987-1989] Teaching Assistant
Teaching Assistant in the Department of Security Studies at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy

Tufts University (Medford, MA)

▶ [1985-1987] German Instructor
German instructor at Tufts University. Taught several introductory semester courses in German to undergraduates

Education

- ▶ [1991] Diploma, Institute for Data Processing and Functional Programming (Frankfurt, Germany) Study of computer science, programming and microeconomics
- ► [1987 –1989] MA, Fletcher School of Law & Diplomacy (Medford, USA)

 Study of international relations, economics and Russian and Eastern European history
- ▶ [1985 –1987] MA, Tufts University (Medford, USA)

Study of drama; wrote MA thesis about "The Function of Theatre in the Totalitarian State: Theatre in the Soviet Occupation Zone/German Democratic Republic 1945 to 1953"

- ► [1982 –1985] BA, University of Tübingen (Germany) Study of German literature, history and philosophy
- ▶ [1982] High School Diploma (Hamburg, Germany)

Computing

▶ Programming Languages

C, C++, Visual Basic, Lotus Notes, Magik, CBase, Cobol, Assembler

▶ Database Management

SQL

▶ Website Design and Development

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

▶ GIS Software

Smallworld Geographical Information System

▶ Audio and Video Editing Software

Audacity, Adobe Premiere Pro

▶ General Software

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint), Adobe Acrobat, Constant Contact

Social Media (Setup, Administration, Content)

Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, YouTube, LinkedIn

Languages

German (native speaker), French (good), Russian (used to be good, now rusty)

Hobbies

Sunfish sailing, theatre, yoga, cooking

Board Memberships

Member of the Board of Directors of the Purchase Community House, Purchase, NY Member of the Board of Directors of SEAS (Society for the Education of American Sailors)